http://peaceriveraudubon.org/legal-disclaimer-privacy-policy/

This policy covers Web sites owned or operated by Peace River Audubon Society (PRAS). We encourage you to take the time to read this privacy policy and those of any Web site you visit. PRAS is a local chapter of The National Audubon Society, which is one of the largest, most effective environmental organizations dedicated to the protection and preservation of birds, other wildlife and their habitats. Since our founding in 1977, we have approached environmental issues in a manner reflected by nature itself –- with balance. Our web site is designed as a tool for those interested in the environment to become more involved in our mission. PRAS is concerned about our visitor’s Internet privacy and is committed to honoring our constituents’ privacy preferences. We recognize that visitors to our site may be concerned about the information they provide to us and how PRAS treats that information.
Consumer Choice
PRAS believes a visitor to our site is the one to best determine:
* Whether — and under what conditions –- a visitor should provide “personally identifiable information” (e.g. data that may be used to identify, contact, or locate a person).
* Whether PRAS should share such information with anyone.
* Whether PRAS may contact you by email.
Informed Consent
If PRAS needs to collect personally identifiable information, a visitor to our site will be alerted and given an opportunity to restrict our use of the information. Every visitor has the right to:
* Know when PRAS is collecting personal information.
* Know what personal information is collected, and the purpose of collection.
* Expect the opportunity to choose whether or not personal information will be provided to third parties.
* Expect reasonable steps to be taken to protect personal information from unauthorized use.
* Expect the opportunity to choose whether or not PRAS may use the information to contact you.
PRIVACY POLICY
You can visit most portions of our website without telling us who you are and without revealing any personal information. The only information we collect from a typical web site visit does not identify you. Rather, it is the name of your Internet service provider (“ISP”), the browser and type of machine you are using, the web site that referred you to us, the pages you request and the date and time you request them. We use this information to generate statistics and measure site activity to improve the usefulness of the site to our visitors.
PRAS does not sell or otherwise disclose such user information outside the organization.
Personal Information Collected
In general, when you visit our Web sites and access information you remain anonymous. We do not require you to register or provide personal information to us to view our site.
There are occasions, however, when we will ask for additional information. We do this to better understand and respond to your needs, and provide you with services that may be valuable to you. PRAS collects email addresses and other personally identifiable data about you when such data is voluntarily submitted. For example, personally identifiable information will be collected in order for you to become a member of PRAS or to register as an environmental activist online. Contact information from order forms is used to send orders, invoices and information about PRAS to you. Some of the features of our site also require registration of personal information. We use this information to track the usage of these features and to help you gain access to the information you need to most benefit the environment. All such information is collected and stored in a manner appropriate to the nature of the data. PRAS makes every effort to insure the secure collection and transmission of sensitive user information using industry accepted data collection and encryption methodologies.
Finally, you may decide to send PRAS personally identifying information, for example, in a message containing information about membership. We will only use this information to identify you and to determine how to respond to the electronic mail. We will not use this information for any purpose other than to resolve the matter identified in the email.
Cookies
What are “Cookies”. A cookie is a small text file sent to your computer’s hard drive by a website’s server. Each time you return to the site that “set” the cookie, the server retrieves its cookie from your computer and thereby knows you are a previous visitor who has returned. Cookies may contain information about your ISP, operating system, browser type, screen resolution and number of colors, your computer’s processor type, your ISP’s server, your Internet protocol address, and what server you were last on. Other information can be added to a cookie, but only information that you give to us.
Use of Cookies
PRAS uses cookies written by our site, but not to obtain information on other Web sites that you may visit. Cookies help us by providing some history about the parts of our sites that you have visited. This enables us to help you navigate our site more easily, to determine what pages are most attractive to our visitors, and to alert you to related pages on our site that may interest you.
Use of Information
We will not provide any of your personal information to other organizations.
Security of Your Credit Card Information
We have made every effort to insure the secure collection and transmission of sensitive user information using industry accepted data collection and encryption methodologies. If you are still concerned about the safety of your credit card information online, you may also submit contributions or other payment to PRAS by mailing a check as directed by instructions on the appropriate pages of our website.
Links to Third Party Sites
We provide links to third party sites. Because we do not control those Web sites, we encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these third party sites. That another web site is linked to our site does not constitute an endorsement by PRAS of the owner of the other site, the content of its site, or its products or services.
How to Unsubscribe from a Mailing list or our Email List
If at any time you wish to stop receiving electronic information from PRAS, or to be removed from our email list, you can unsubscribe from that list as explained in each message.
Children 13 and Under
In any section of the site that requests personal information, visitors 13 years of age and under are reminded to obtain permission from an adult before supplying the requested information. In addition, PRAS does not actively advertise products in any section of the site intended specifically for children (such as “WatchList for Kids”).
Questions
PRAS welcomes comments and questions on this policy. We are dedicated to protecting your personal information, and will make every reasonable effort to keep that information secure. If you have any questions, please contact us. Due to the rapidly evolving technologies on the Internet, we may occasionally update this policy. All revisions will be posted to this site. The revised Privacy Policy will apply to all data collected by PRAS, both prior to and subsequent to the Revised Policy’s effective date.
Based upon the National Audubon Society Privacy Policy of January 2004.
Email:
Leave this field empty if you're human:
Connect With Us!
Learn How To Get Involved
Events Calendar
« December 2020
»
PRAS – December Meeting Cancelled (Webinar with Dave and Tammy McQuade, ‘Their Big Year 2019’)
